# **Christopher Woodside**

## Full-Stack Web Developer

#### **PROFILE**

After graduating from Wabash College with an honors degree in History, I worked for several years as a productivity consultant. I also spent time working as a business and systems analyst for a large insurance company. In each capacity, I worked as an analytical problem solver, and I established a solid track record of improving processes, managing diverse projects, and finding unique solutions to overcome obstacles and work within a team. I seek to use web-development as a way to connect people, and as a way to use web applications or connected products to improve people's lives.

## **PROJECTS**

### **CTZN**

My capstone project, CTZN is a web application is designed to help citizens follow the progress of local, state, and federal legislation, and to help the user take actions related to it. Users are able to search for bills, add them to their queue, and set "action" reminders which prompt them to contact their representatives through various means of communication or attend an event or meeting. CTZN makes use of Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, and various public APIs, such as ProPublica's Congress API and OpenStates API. I chose to build this app to streamline the process of following legislation and taking actions to support or oppose it.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Full-Stack Web Developer**

Actualize | Chicago, IL | 2016 - Present

- 15-week full-stack web development training learning Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, etc.
- Worked in teams and learned to pair program
- Completed daily coding exercises and researched coding methods and skills independently
- Built a fully functional web app, CTZN, from scratch

## **Business Systems Analyst & Project Leader**

National General Insurance | Chicago, IL | 2012 - 2015

- Led research and business analysis for insurance system enhancement, conversion, and integration projects
- Developed system testing plans, requirements, and project timelines for 8-month company merger projects
- Collaborated with internal users and development team to catalog, debug, and test various system errors and malfunctions and worked with state agencies and offshore development teams during project design and implementation

#### Management & Productivity Consultant

Advanced Productivity Services | Chicago, IL | 2010 - 2011, 2006 - 2008

- Constructed work-flows and business analyses to evaluate various departments and identify areas of productivity improvements
- Designed and implemented management operating systems and workforce forecasting tools

#### **SKILLS**

**JavaScript** 

Ruby

Rails

HTML CSS

Git

AngularJS

SQL

PostgreSQL

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Actualize**

Full-Stack Web Developer | 2016

#### Wabash College

BA, History, Spanish & International Studies | 2002 - 2006

## COMMUNITY

## W.A.B.A.S.H. Day

Serving meals at Ronald McDonald House, and cleaning & yard work for Evanston women's shelter with local alumni association.

2011 - 2015

## CONTACT

Chicago, IL (231) 838-8573 christopherwoodside@gmail.com

github.com/ceedubs84 linkedin.com/in/chriswoodside medium.com/@christopherwoodside